I wanted to play Deus Ex : Mankind Divided,
but my CPU won't allow Clothes Physics,
so the game is essentially unplayable.
Therefore I am stuck with this 9 year old game.
Human Revolution.
I don't like the game's subtitle,
because aren't all revolutions human?
A better title would be
Deus Ex: Technology is very spooky, or
Deus Ex: I forgot to quicksave.
It begins with a cinematic.
We see this man talking to anonymous people
about a female bioship or something. i'm
sure it's important but I can't focus
because why do they all use the default
profile picture, at least one of them
would use a koala. We cut to a news
broadcast, a billionaire has said
something he shouldn't and now people are
angry, so the future isn't all that different.
This is our main character Adam Jensen
and he's the head of security at
Sarif Industries, a company that
produces...
...cat food?
This is Dr. Reid. She's an almost perfect
girlfriend in a video game, so she's
not gonna be around.
We are on our way to meet CEO David
Sarif and in an elevator we meet Pritchard
the head of cybersecurity who is
actually mad about the fact that even
in the future cybersecurity still isn't
as cool as physical security, no matter
how hard Hollywood tries.
Apparently we're going to Washington with some scientists.
Then an alarm goes off, OH SHIT,
has there been an accident?
No, thank God we're only getting attacked
by mercenaries.
They beat up Jensen and take her. Girlfriend is gone and we are going after the people responsible.
Then was any of this really necessary if
you're going to be stealing the story
from Mario Brothers.
the shoot Jensen and
the intro starts.
Doctors rescue him but at what cost?
No cost, he only gains a bunch of stuff
and becomes half android. That means he
can make a bunch of anti robot jokes. I
can't give you an example because that
would be robotist.
David Sarif wants to
meet us in a helicopter and on the
helipad we meet our helicopter driver,
who wants to talk to us but I don't want
to talk to the help.
Sarif gives us our first mission. A
bunch of employees and more importantly
a weapon has been taken hostage by the
anti-augmentation terrorist
Zeke Sanders, grandson of a presidential
candidate that was a closet Wall Street Banker.
David asks if you want a lethal, or a non-lethal weapon for a more stealthy approach.
Stealth?! I'm not at my
parents house trying to microwave popcorn,
I'm here to kill.
So we go in
guns-a-blazing killing everything we see,
then we rescue the hostages by hacking a
bomb. Hacking is important in Deus Ex, it's
also the only game to feature realistic
hacking. You might think hacking looks
like this, but that's what the security
lobby want you to think, or you can just
look up codes online like me.
Jensen is one month younger than the real me, you should be in bed by now young man
Our child protagonist finds the weapon, but someone is hacking it.
Then the hacker
kills himself against his own will, and
now everyone is freaking out because
mystery. What they don't consider is
maybe this guy is just fucking with them.
Time to meet Sanders to get some answers,
but he has a hostage. You have to
talk to him.
(evil laughter)
During the mission debriefing
they realize that Sanders was tricked by
whoever did this, and we need to analyze
these augmentations, but SWAT has taken
his corpse that we totally had dibs on.
Who do they think they are, the cops?! So
the second mission is to break into the
police morgue. Now you can walk the
streets of Detroit. Don't know why you would want to.
Here is where Jensen says the now famous quote:
"I never asked for the procedures"
Police station:
The two main ways to get into the morgue
is to either talk to this guy about your feelings
or sneaking from the sewers, but
they are forgetting something.
No one actually told me this was a
stealth game
(dramatic music plays)
Ehh, what's up doc?
Fun fact: killed like
12 cops, never comes up.
The corpses' brainy thingy has been modified by some
techie mumbo-jumbo yes those were the
exact words they used. We take them to
Pritchard so he can analyze it. We find out
that the guy was controlled by some sort
of mega hacker hiding in Highland Park.
Welcome to an abandoned Factory, it's always an abandoned Factory.
It's those guys that attacked us.
In the slowest elevator in the universe we find
out the facility is owned by FEMA.
What is a FEMA? In the real world it's a
government agency that fistfights hurricanes,
but in the Deus Ex world
I don't know what they do, but they have a
prison camp and we are in that prison
camp. We meet up with the guys and boss fight
I have no idea how to beat this guy,
but I have a fire extinguisher in case
he tries to kill me with secondhand
smoking.
Don't dodge! Works every time.
The bosses final words are you should
totally go to Hengsha, Shanghai. Here's an
address. This is not a trap. So Serif
decides that we should do that.
That's stupid, you're stupid. Outside Sarif's
office we meet Taggart, who is the leader
of the anti turning humans into kick-ass
robots movement.
That makes him the worst person in history.
This is what Hengsha looks like right
now but in 10 years is going to look like this.
The address leads to a place
named Hengsha Court Gardens but it's
been locked down by private police.
Oh my God.
Can Jensen not go one day without killing cops?!
The cannon fodder leads
us to this computer. The hacker who's been
hacking us is some dutch guy, but he
escaped and he's trying to get back to
his home country of, uhh...
...Holland?
So wait, the
address this guy gave us actually helped?!
Of course their actions, FEMA, private
government police.
It's so obvious who's behind this.
Morons.
Our enemies are morons.
To escape, the hacker got help from a Cantonese
gangster named Tong. Actually his name is
but he wrote his surname first, for
some reason. Tong tells us where the
Dutchman is. Wait, that's it you-you're
gonna tell me? No mission or anything?
Screw you Tong.
Hello I am Dutch hacker. I was
hired to hack you by your biggest competitor
That's way too obvious and
reasonable. Then some soldiers show up.
They have the place surrounded but I
could sneak past them.
It's way easier to sneak past a dead
person.
Time to infiltrate our biggest competitor.
I don't want to be discovered
because that might give our company
bad press but you can bet I'm gonna
steal so much office supplies.
In a computer we find the surveillance
recording that shows the company's CEO
talking to.. WOW we still don't know his
name.
She talks about a lady named Eliza and a
city from Chinese legend called
"Moon Tea Real"
So we go to the top floor so we can
question her, and she tricks us because
Jensen is a fucking idiot.
Oh no! Is that 10 people?!
Jensen tells the pilot that he wants to
go to Canada because he thinks Eliza
might be reporter Eliza Cassan.
Yes, he knows that there are more than one
Eliza in Canada but you have to start
somewhere.
Welcome to Baguette, Canada. But the news
station is empty. There she is.
Oh shit, she's a hologram. Oh shit,
soldiers. These aren't soldiers sent by
the people after us. Every news station
has in-house paramilitary in case another
station tries to steal their headlines.
Eliza's in the basement and she's a
supercomputer not even surprised.
Boss fight!
Wow, she really should have worn a helmet.
Eliza shows us that Taggart's sidekick
helped with the kidnapping, and we should talk to Sarif.
Adam, Illuminati did this.
Of course.
Who are the Illuminati? It's this
world government conspiracy from 2014
created by videogame montage parodies.
Time to find Taggart's assistant. Taggart,
tell me where your assistant is, or I
with blow your head off.
He's in a sewer, and very sad that Taggart
threw him under the bus.
Apparently the scientists have a tracker
and they are still sending out the
signal, but no one checked because Sarif
doesn't do paid overtime, so no one cared.
Now he's planning on killing himself and
I have to talk him out of it because I
am the only one doing the killing here.
Back at Sarif HQ, we are supposed to meet
Sarif but instead we meet the inventor of
augmentation who is whining about how
his inventions has caused so many problems.
If you don't want your invention to be
used for evil you shouldn't invent anything.
The inventor of the machine-gun
wanted it to be a can opener.
Then Sarif finally shows up. They've tracked down one of
the scientists. Back to Hengsha.
Hey, they shot us down!!
Hey, they are killing our pilot! How are
we ever gonna replace her?
A new pilot, that could take days.
This signal leads to a place full of
triad members. Well, was full of triad members.
The scientist is in this room.
TONG?! Oh my God. Tong was a Sarif
scientist all along.
What a twist. Oh, the trackers in his arm,
that he stole from the scientist, who is now dead.
But Tong knows where the others
are. In the docks, there is a boat owned by
the bad guys.
Oh that's it. Thats that's all you have.
Screw you Tong. Fuck it, let's ride the boat.
A couple of days later we wake up
in Singapore. The scientists are here.
They got an all-expenses six-month paid
trip to Singapore and the only thing
they had to give up was their freedom.
How do I become a scientist? They have
been working on the bioship but no one cares,
Where's Dr. Reid? She's deeper in the
facility, but first we have to fight this boss,
that has been hyped up so many
times. This will be epic.
There she is, and Adam gets angry. She
thinks it's because she was working for
them, but it's actually because what kind
of asshole gets an apartment in a
tropical country then doesn't tell
anyone. Does she not know of hotel costs?
Then we find out the bad guy behind it all.
That's the least surprising thing ever.
They have distributed a bunch of
biochips. He activates them and everyone
with augmentations go crazy. Then the game
does what we all expected from the start
and becomes a zombie game. We meet up
with the inventor and he's all, uhh my
inventions, and Jensen is all, your
fucking idiot, and then he agrees. So we
head towards the basement to shut down
the biochips. On our way we meet Taggart, and he
says "Wanna join the Illuminati?
Best tacos on the planet". Then Sarif and he
says "Corporations: Aw yeah!" and I might
have to agree with him because if not
YouTube might not consider my videos
advertiser friendly. Time to shut down
the reactor, but oh no, it's her and
she does stuff.
I have no idea how to beat this boss.
I have no idea how i beat
the boss. Now we get to pick our ending.
Do what the Illuminati wants, but then
someone on YouTube might expose you,
Tell everyone the truth about Illuminati and
everything.
His main argument was think of their
faces it will be hilarious.
Or you can help corporations. #EmojiBae. or
kill everything, but there is a fifth ending.
All four endings at the same time. The
thing about humans is that when things
get too confusing we give up. After four
days all of humanity decided, let's
pretend none of this ever happened. And
that is the Kilian Experience.